makemytripdeals.com 2011-12-02

# Privacy Policy - MakeMyTrip.com

|   
---  
As a registered member of MakeMyTrip.com, you will be entitled to savings and benefits on airfares, hotel reservations, holiday packages and car rentals, among other travel services. In addition, look forward to receiving monthly newsletters and exclusive promotions offering special deals.  
That's why we've provided this Privacy Policy, which sets forth our policies regarding the collection, use and protection of the personal information of those using the MakeMyTrip.com website. Personal information means information that can be linked to a specific individual, such as name, address, telephone number, e - mail address, and credit card number.  
We encourage you to review our Privacy Policy, and become familiar with it, but you should know that we do not sell or rent our customers' personal information to third parties.  
Please note that we review our Privacy Policy from time to time, and we may make periodic changes to the policy in connection with that review. Therefore, you may wish to bookmark this page and/or periodically review this page to make sure you have the latest version. Regardless of later updates, we will abide by the privacy practices described to you in this Privacy Policy at the time you provided us with your personal information.  
   
This Privacy Policy explains the following:  
   
| What personal information we collect from you and how we use it?  
| With whom (if anyone) your personal information is shared?  
| How you can opt - out of receiving our promotional e - mails?  
| What safeguards we have in place to protect your personal information?  
| Other information you should know about your privacy?  
  |    
|   
---  
| What personal information we collect from you and how we use it?  
---  
When browsing our site, you are not required to provide any personal information unless and until you choose to make a purchase or sign up for one of our e-mail newsletters or other services as described below.  
Making a Purchase  
In order to purchase travel and/or related services through our site, you must provide us with certain personal information such as your name, credit card number and expiration date, credit card billing address, telephone number, e - mail address and the name or names of the person(s) traveling (if not you). We may also ask you for other personal information, such as your frequent traveler numbers. We require this information to process, fulfill and confirm your reservations and transactions and keep you informed of each transaction's status. If you are making a reservation for one or more travelers other than yourself, you must confirm and represent that each of these other travelers have agreed, in advance, that you may disclose their personal information to us.  
Member Registration  
If you choose to become a registered member of MakeMyTrip.com site, you must provide your name, address, telephone number, e-mail address, a unique login name, password, and password validation, and a password hint to help you remember your password. This information is collected on the registration form for several reasons including but not limited to:  
|   
---  
* | Personal identification  
* | To complete air, hotel, car, and other reservations  
* | To allow us to contact you for customer service purposes, if necessary  
* | To customize the content of our site to strive to meet your specific needs; and/or  
* | To make product or other improvements to our site. In addition, we need your e - mail address to confirm your new member registration and each reservation you transact on our site. As a MakeMyTrip.com site member you will also occasionally receive updates from us about fare sales in your area, special offers, new MakeMyTrip services, and other noteworthy items. However, you may choose at any time to no longer receive these types of e - mail messages. Please see our Opt - Out Policy described below for details.  
   
Member Profile   
As a MakeMyTrip.com site member, you can choose to complete your online profile by providing us with travel preferences, frequent - traveler or affinity numbers, credit card billing information, paper ticket delivery address, and other personal information. This information is primarily used to assist you in making reservations quickly without having to type in the same information repeatedly. For example, you can store your airline frequent - flyer numbers so that when your make a reservation on that airline, we may automatically pre - fill the frequent - flyer number input box for you.   
   
Online Surveys   
MakeMyTrip values opinions and comments from members, so we frequently conduct online surveys. Participation in these surveys is entirely optional. Typically, the information is aggregated, and used to make improvements to the MakeMyTrip.com site and its services and to develop appealing content, features and promotions for MakeMyTrip.com site members. Survey participants are anonymous unless otherwise stated in the survey.   
Promotions & Sweepstakes   
MakeMyTrip frequently sponsors promotions and sweepstakes to give MakeMyTrip.com site members the opportunity to win great travel and travel - related prizes. Information collected by us for such activities may include contact information and survey questions. We use contact information to notify contest winners and survey information to develop promotions and product improvements to the MakeMyTrip.com site.  
   
Automatic Logging of Session Data  
We automatically log generic information about your computer's connection to the Internet, which we call "session data", that is anonymous and not linked to any personal information. Session data consists of things such as IP address, operating system and type of browser software being used and the activities conducted by the user while on MakeMyTrip.com site. An IP address is a number that lets computers attached to the internet, such as our web servers, know where to send data back to the user, such as the pages of the site the user wishes to view. We collect session data because it helps us analyze such things as what items visitors are likely to click on most, the way visitors are clicking through the site, how many visitors are surfing to various pages on the site, how long visitors to the site are staying and how often they are visiting. It also helps us diagnose problems with our servers and lets us better administer our systems. Although such information does not identify any visitor personally, it is possible to determine from an IP address a visitor's Internet Service Provider (ISP), and the approximate geographic location of his or her point of connectivity.  
   
Cookies  
"Cookies" are small pieces of information that are stored by your browser on your computer's hard drive. There are many myths circulating about cookies, but you should know that cookies are only read by the server that placed them, and are unable to do such things as run programs on your computer, plant viruses or harvest your personal information. The use of cookies is very common on the Internet and MakeMyTrip's use of cookies is similar to that of such sites as Expedia and Orbitz, as well as Yahoo!, CNN.com and other reputable online companies.  
First and foremost, you can rest assured that no personally identifiable information ("PII") about you (e.g., name, address, etc.) is gathered or stored in the cookies placed by the MakeMyTrip.com site and, as a result, none can be passed on to any third parties.  
Cookies allow us to serve you better and more efficiently, and to personalize your experience at our site. MakeMyTrip uses cookies to personalize your experience on the MakeMyTrip.com site, and with respect to advertisements. As to the former, these types of cookies allow you to log in without having to type your log - in name each time (only your password is needed. We may also use such cookies to display an advertisement to you while you are on MakeMyTrip.com site or to send you a "Best Day to Buy" email (or similar emails - assuming you have not opted out of receiving such emails) focusing on destinations in which we think you might be interested. None of this information is passed to any third party, and is used solely by us to provide you with a better user experience on MakeMyTrip.com site.   
A cookie may also be placed by our advertising server. Such cookies are used only for purposes of tracking the effectiveness of advertising served by us on our site and no PII is gathered from you by the use of these cookies, nor is this information shared with any third parties. Similarly, a cookie may be placed by our third - party advertising companies. These companies may use aggregated statistics about your visits to this and other web sites in order to provide advertisements about travel - related goods and services that you may be interested in. The information they collect does not include your PII.  
The third - party advertising companies may also employ technology that is used to measure the effectiveness of ads. Any such information is anonymous. They may use this anonymous information about your visits to this and other sites in order to provide advertisements about goods and services of potential interest to you. No PII is collected during this process. The information is anonymous, and does not link online actions to an identifiable person. If you would like more information, and want to explore the option of not having this information collected by third - party advertisers.  
Most Web browsers automatically accept cookies. Of course, by changing the options on your web browser or using certain software programs, you can control how and whether cookies will be accepted by your browser. MakeMyTrip supports your right to block any unwanted Internet activity, especially that of unscrupulous websites. However, blocking MakeMyTrip cookies may disable certain features on the MakeMyTrip.com site, and may make it impossible to purchase or use certain services available on the MakeMyTrip.com site. Please note that it is possible to block cookie activity from certain websites while permitting cookies from sites you trust, like MakeMyTrip.   
Other  
From time to time we may add or enhance services available on MakeMyTrip.com site. To the extent these services are provided, and used by you, we will use the information you provide to facilitate the service requested. For example, if you email us with a question, we will use your email address, name, nature of the question, etc. to respond to your question. We may also store such information to assist us in making the site the better and easier to use.   
   
With whom (if anyone) your personal information is shared?   
When you reserve or purchase travel services through MakeMyTrip, we must provide certain of your personal information to the airline, hotel, car - rental agency, travel agency or other involved third party to enable the successful fulfillment of your travel arrangements. However, we do not sell or rent individual customer names or other personal information to third parties. We use non - personally identifiable information in aggregate form to build higher quality, more useful online services by performing statistical analysis of the collective characteristics and behavior of our customers and visitors, and by measuring demographics and interests regarding specific areas of the MakeMyTrip.com Site. We may provide anonymous statistical information based on this data to suppliers, advertisers, affiliates and other current and potential business partners. We may also use such aggregate data to inform these third parties as to the number of people who have seen and clicked on links to their web sites. Occasionally, MakeMyTrip will hire a third party to act on our behalf for projects such as market - research surveys and contest - entry processing and will provide information to these third parties specifically for use in connection with these projects. The information we provide to such third parties is protected by a confidentiality agreement and is to be used solely for completing the specific project.   
   
How you can opt-out of receiving our promotional e-mails?  
At any time, you may unsubscribe from our Real Deals, Insider, or other newsletter or similar services through the "My Account" link on the MakeMyTrip.com Site home page. As a member or promotion/sweepstakes entrant, you will occasionally receive e-mail updates from us about fare sales in your area, special offers, new MakeMyTrip services, and other noteworthy items. We hope you will find these updates interesting and informative. Of course, if you would rather not receive them, please click on the "unsubscribe" link or follow the instructions in each e - mail message or send us an email [unsubscribe@makemytrip.com](mailto:unsubscribe@makemytrip.com). MakeMyTrip reserves the right to limit membership to those who will accept e - mails. Members will be notified via e - mail prior to any actions taken.   
   
What safeguards we have in place to protect your personal information?   
All payments on the MakeMyTrip.com site is Verisign SSL secured. This means all personal information you provide to MakeMyTrip is transmitted using SSL (Secure Socket Layer) encryption. SSL is a proven coding system that lets your browser automatically encrypt, or scramble, data before you send it to us. The same process happens when you make travel purchases on the MakeMyTrip.com site.  
   
What other information should I know about my privacy?   
MakeMyTrip.com site contains links to other web sites. Please note that when you click on one of these links, you are entering another web site for which MakeMyTrip has no responsibility. We encourage you to read the privacy statements of all such sites as their policies may be materially different from this Privacy Policy. Of course, you are solely responsible for maintaining the secrecy of your passwords, and your MakeMyTrip.com site membership account information. Please be very careful, responsible, and alert with this information, especially whenever you're online.   
In addition to the circumstances described above, MakeMyTrip may disclose the MakeMyTrip.com site member information if required to do so by law, court order, as requested by other government or law enforcement authority, or in the good faith belief that disclosure is otherwise necessary or advisable including, without limitation, to protect the rights or properties of MakeMyTrip or any or all of its affiliates, associates, employees, directors or officers or when we have reason to believe that disclosing the information is necessary to identify, contact or bring legal action against someone who may be causing interference with our rights or properties, whether intentionally or otherwise, or when anyone else could be harmed by such activities. In addition, if MakeMyTrip or substantially all of its assets are acquired, our customer information will most likely also be transferred in connection with such acquisition  
This policy is effective as of April 15, 2005. Any material changes in the way MakeMyTrip uses personal information will be described in future versions of this Privacy Statement. Of course, you may always submit concerns regarding our Privacy Statement or our privacy practices via email to [privacy@makemytrip.com](mailto:privacy@makemytrip.com). Please reference the privacy policy in your subject line. MakeMyTrip will attempt to respond to all reasonable concerns or inquiries within five business days of receipt.   
Thank you for using MakeMyTrip.com!
